

MING SHUN KWEK

mingshun1998@hotmail.com



Singapore, Singapore



Student of Software

www.linkedin.com/in/kwek-ming-shun

0

SUMMARY

Computer Engineering Graduate from National University of Singapore and current Singapore Industry Scholar at Micron Technology. Strong communicator with a determined work ethic. Forward-thinking development professional with expertise in Python, Java and other programming languages. Committed to continuous learning and gaining experience across diverse fields to contribute meaningfully to the world of technology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Strategic Planning Engineer (Data Analytics)

Micron Semiconductor Asia Pte Ltd | 2023 - Present

- Led capacity planning for CMP manufacturing area through coordination with senior management on engineering changes and optimizing capital expenditures (CAPEX), saving \$12.1M in FY24 for tooling modifications.
- Streamlined departmental workflows by developing Python scripts and managing historical data sets using backend SQL database management, enhancing data retrieval and analysis.
- Spearheaded discussions with Micron's Smart Manufacturing Global Team to develop capacity planning software aligned with current industry practices, intended for widespread use by Micron's planning engineers worldwide.

Java Software Developer (Intern)

Integro Technologies Pte Ltd | 2021 - 2022

- Collaborated on Collateral and Limits Management Product (CLIMS), resolving frontend UI issues in JSP by applying industry-standard debugging processes, successfully resolving over 30 issues.
- Troubleshooted backend bugs that made used of Java Spring and Hibernate frameworks, helped identified root causes and formulated corrective action recommendations.
- Created, modified, and maintained software documentation and specifications.

Contracts/Projects Assistant

YL Integrated PTE LTD | 2018 - 2019

- Analyzed floor plans to calculate the required lighting and fire emergency equipment for tender projects, facilitating accurate purchases while striving for CAPEX savings.
- Managed communication between suppliers and the company, addressing inquiries regarding quotations and purchase orders.
- Mentored a team of 3 employees, overseeing their training and professional development.

Sergeant, 1st Battalion Singapore Guards

Singapore Armed Forces (National Service) | 2017 - 2018

- Planned mission objectives and collaborated with full-time servicemen to optimize battle plans and develop efficient routes for mission success
- Facilitated the training of 30+ recruits as an instructor, teaching and mentoring enlistees. Transitioned to a leadership role post-graduation from Basic Training, taking responsibility for recruits during their active service.

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering 2019 – 2023

Nanyang Junior College

Singapore-Cambridge GCE Advanced Level Diploma 2015 – 2016

SKILLS

- Java/ SQL/ Python Programming
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Code versioning (Git)
- Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team

CERTIFICATIONS

- Singapore-Industry Scholarship (SgIS) @ Micron
- NUS Software Development Orbital Programme (ApollAdvanced Certification
- HSK Chinese Proficiency Test (Level 5) Certification